Guide to the Wallace Stegner Papers, 1961-1964
Department of Special Collections
Wallace Stegner Papers,
1961-1964
Special Collections M0054
Special Collections Staff
2.5 linear feet
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
The manuscript of Beyond the Hundredth Meridian, correspondence regarding Stegner's research on John W. Powell, and the manuscripts of Women on the Wall and Sabrina were received from Wallace Stegner in 1961. In August 1963 Stegner delivered photocopies of diaries used in his research for The Mormon Trail. Except for those of Jacob Norton and John Bond, these diaries are unpublished and were obtained from Brigham Young University or the Utah State Historical Society. In December of 1964 the Powell Report manuscript was received, also from Stegner.
CONTAINER LIST
- Beyond the Hundredth Meridian (1961), book on John W. Powell.
  - Beyond the Hundredth Meridian typescript (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Beyond the Hundredth Meridian typescript (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beyond the Hundredth Meridian typescript (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Beyond the Hundredth Meridian typescript (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Beyond the Hundredth Meridian typescript (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Beyond the Hundredth Meridian typescript, and notes for books (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Powell, W.C., letters to Chicago Tribune, 1971-1872 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Powell: miscellaneous correspondence with private individuals (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Powell: Huntington Library; miscellaneous libraries, museums, universities, publications and societies (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Powell: Department of the Interior, Geological Survey, etc. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Powell: Department of Agriculture; other federal offices and government agencies (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Powell: Smithsonian, Bureau of American Ethnology, Mae Tucker (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Powell: miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Powell Report: typescripts of introduction, index, footnotes, etc. with manuscript corrections and editing (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Powell Report: author's copy with manuscript corrections and editing (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Women on the Wall
  - Women on the Wall manuscript (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Sabrina
  - Sabrina I manuscript (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sabrina II manuscript (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Sabrina Ia manuscript (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Sabrina IIa manuscript (Box 3, Folder 4)
- The Mormon Trail research materials
  - Oliver Boardman Huntington: diary, 1842-1900 (copy) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Patience Loader: portions of a diary (copy) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Pioneer Co., 1861 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - John Pulsipher: portions of a journal, 1848 (copy from BYU) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - John Pulsipher: diary, vol. 1, March 1835 - October 1894 (copy of typescript) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Oliver Boardman Huntington: portions of a journal, 1848 (copy from BYU) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - George Laub: portions of a journal, 1952 (copy from BYU) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Journal of Amasa M. Lyman kept by Albert Harrington, April 8 - September 10, 1847 (copy from BYU) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hosea Stout: portions of a journal, 1848 (copy from BYU) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Appleton M. Harmon: diary (copy of typescript from the Utah Historical Records Survey), part I (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Harmon diary part II (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Levi Jackman: journal. Pioneer Personal Sketches at end. Mrs. Nicholas Gourley Teeples about her husband. (copy from U.S.H.S.) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Journal of Immigration Co. "...into the great Salt Lake Valley," 1852 (copy from U.S.H.S.) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Record of Norton Jacob, ed. by C. Edward Jacob and Ruth S. Jacob, 1949 (opy) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bond, John, Handcarts West in '56, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Wolf Willow
  - Wolf Willow, front matter and pp. 1-156 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Wolf Willow, pp. 157-241 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Wolf Willow, pp. 242-338, end (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Paul F. Hoye to Wallace Stegner, May 5, 1971, re: "Discovery"; Harwood P. Hinton to Wallace Stegner, July 2, 1965, re: Arizona and the West (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Remember about the West" manuscript with corrections (Box 5, Folder 8)